this is the Apple Vision Pro headset it
starts at three and a half thousand
dollars it's going to very possibly
replace the smartphone one day so how
does it work what's good about it what's
bad about it and then most importantly
why on Earth is Apple doing this so it's
a pair of goggles that you wear over
your eyes I wouldn't exactly say they
make you look cool like these auto
tinting sunglasses I'm testing for
another video kind of do wow but I think
the key thing that Apple's trying to go
for here is to make it look seamless
they've designed it in a way but even
though there is more Tech going on in
this headset than literally any other
consumer tech product on the market
right now that it doesn't feel like a
burden so
how does it work well the main thing
that you're going to be seeing is the
screens there's two of them there's one
for each of your eyes which you know in
the real world each of your eyes sees
things from a slightly different angle
and that's what gives things a sense of
depth this allows them to recreate that
same effect but in the digital world so
it will feel like you can reach out and
touch the things you're seeing which is
not completely new but it does seem like
one of the most convincing applications
of that in large part because of how
good the screens are to give you an idea
the iPhone screen is already pretty
sharp right like you would struggle even
if you stare right up close to discern
individual pixels on this well the
screens on these glasses have can't even
make this stuff up 64 times the pixel
density of the iPhone that's almost
impossible to even visualize but they're
doing that because even when your eyes
are right up next to these screens they
don't want you to ever see an individual
pixel so yes this thing is really really
expensive but we need to make something
very clear that this is not just a pair
of movie glasses the kind you've been
able to buy already for the last 15
years that you stick on your face and
you watch TBR this is Apple fleshing out
what's very likely to become the
replacement to the smartphone one day a
way to watch things yes but also a way
to communicate to express yourself and
one day be able to use all the apps that
you've gotten used to but in a whole new
dimension it's the equivalent of not
just having like a 6.5 inch screen like
I have on my iPhone right now but a
screen that at all time can fill your
entire vision and if your entire vision
is just display then you have basically
unlimited room for your apps and so as
you can probably imagine to achieve that
the hardware also has to be a lot more
than just screens on the inside so
you'll notice if you look at the bottom
this thing is covered in sensors you've
got 3D cameras you've got lidar scanners
for depth detection and more so the 3D
cameras can continue to feed you a 3D
view of the room you're in just like
your eyes would normally do and then
because you've got these depth sensors
you can place your apps within these
rooms and what I thought was just such a
cool touch is that they actually have a
presence you'll see them casting a
shadow on your desk or if you're
watching a movie you will see the glow
from the screen spill over into your
surroundings don't get me wrong there
are some very legitimate concerns about
tech like this and I'm getting there but
at the same time this has been the wet
dream of every developer for the last 30
years and so some part of me is kind of
shocked that in one Fell Swoop it's not
just here but this well thought out
already and then the other thing that
you can tell apple is trying to push
here is that this is not you losing
yourself in your own little world and
your own content this is a social
experience and for that the inside of a
headset is lined with a second set of
cameras which kind of feels like the
next iteration of how phones right now
have a rear set of cameras and a front
set of cameras and this has a few
implications it can a record your eyes
and then use its General understanding
of what your face looks like to turn
those eye Expressions you make into a
full-on photorealistic digital avatar
for when you're having FaceTime calls so
it will look like your entire face even
though it isn't but then also it can
project a 3D model of what your eyes are
actually doing underneath this headset
to the external screen yes the outside
is a 3D screen too and yes the image
that other people see will change based
on the angle that they're looking at you
from and this is
kind of weird I'm definitely not used to
it and it's not something I ever
expected a headset to do but it does
make you look like a present when you're
doing things that are augmented reality
where you can see other people in the
background it's making it clear to them
that you can see them which does at
least somewhat address that that kind of
uneasiness that you'd get by not
actually knowing what someone wearing
one of these headsets is looking at and
then when you switch to something that's
a full screen experience your external
screen will Cloud over to again
communicate that to the people around
you and then the third thing that these
internal cameras do assisted by some
tiny little infrared sensors is that
these are how you control the thing and
this moves me on to the things that I
really like about the Vision Pro because
yeah really it tracks the pupils in your
eyes it learns your irises and uses that
as the way to authenticate you and
automatically unlock itself it knows
exactly where you're looking and
effectively makes your eyes the cursor
to hover over things I was a little
nervous that they then make you have to
Blink every time you wanted to click
something thank God they haven't because
that would be a Fast Track ticket to a
headache instead you can just use your
finger your glasses will know where your
fingers are because of these cameras
which have a massive field of view and
from the moment that I first saw this I
thought yes this is the most natural way
to interact with a VR or ar headset it's
going to make it feel like an extension
of you and I'm so glad that you don't
have to reach out and hold your hands up
like this because that's gimmicky the
fact that you can just rest it on a
table or your lap and still use it that
is going to be the key to it feeling
seamless kind of like when we first saw
touchscreen phones that didn't need
styluses you just interact with your
fingers and I mean the rest is history
plus you do also get Siri to type things
with your voice and you can also link it
with your normal Apple keyboards and
mice and then you've got the power when
I first saw that Apple was making a
headset I initially thought oh okay well
it's going to require you to have an
iPhone and that iPhone is probably going
to be the main source of computing power
and it'll just stream to the headset
which is just where you view it that
would have been the simple way to do
this but apple is instead very clearly
drawing a line that separates this from
just being an accessory to the phone
this is a brand new product category
with a brand new operating system for
the first time since they launched the
Apple watch nearly 10 years ago and with
that it's got its own laptop quality M2
chipset inside of it as well as a
dedicated R1 chip that's going to focus
on processing the insane amounts of data
from the 12 cameras 5 sensors and six
mics on the thing and then to keep the
whole thing Juiced up got quite a weird
solution in that it's an external
battery pack that you keep in your
pocket and my very first thought was
this doesn't feel very Apple it's not
the seamless polished perfect solution
and the fact that it only lasts like two
hours on a charge definitely makes it
feel a little bit less bleeding edge but
I do think it was the right decision
because it allows you to redistribute a
large part of the weight and size of the
headset which if it's being designed for
daily wear is really really important
it's still not light by any stretch of
the imagination I mean it is made of
glass and aluminum mostly but it's not
bat B it means that it's completely
Standalone and portable having a battery
and having your own chip means it
doesn't require you to be plugged into a
console or a PC it C allows you to
quickly swap out batteries instead of
needing to actually take the headset off
and recharge it although to be sure
based on the cost of the headset itself
I don't think many people are going to
have spare budget to buy extra batteries
but D what I think is the most important
part of this is that it's allowed them
to get the product out sooner if Apple
had waited for the day where they could
get this much power in this kind of form
factor with an integrated battery this
Tech might well have been sitting on a
shelf for another 10 years but the fact
that they are putting out now means not
necessarily that now is the time to buy
one but that in 10 years time this Tech
is going to be in a much better place
than if they waited for the first
iteration to be perfect it's also going
to be a really comfortable way to
consume content so I took an 11 hour
flight to get here I pre-downloaded some
podcasts on my phone but the whole time
while doing that I was just thinking
this doesn't feel like the ideal way to
consume that content whereas The Vision
Pro would have an even more immersive
screen that even though it's smaller
will feel a lot bigger have speakers
that fire directly into my ears it'll
rest naturally over my eyes so that I
don't need to hold it or prop it up to
get just the right angle in a way this
one product has the best parts of every
one of Apple's other products baked into
it the connectivity of the iPhone I mean
the current Vision Pro does not have a
SIM slot in but there's no reason why
the Next Generation couldn't the display
quality of the five thousand dollar Pro
display xdr the computing power of the
MacBook not to mention the whole other
extra Dimension it's adding and then
cameras this is where you really feel
the benefit of wearing your Tech in the
sense though all of a sudden you don't
need to take anything out to take a
photo or video it's one button so you
can experience a moment while also at
the same time resting easy knowing that
you're recording that moment in the
exact same way that you experienced it
in full three dimensions I mean this is
a huge deal we've been capturing photos
and videos for over the last 50 years in
two Dimensions so if this headset or the
idea of this headset catches on and
becomes mainstream that changes the
entire Paradigm of what it means to
capture a memory but there are also some
things that do concern me for example I
find it kind of funny that in the same
presentation Apple talked about how it's
introducing a feature that encourages
you to keep screens further away from
your face and then introduce your device
to keep screens one inch from your face
then there's a next thing which is that
there's already very little separation
between us and our technology you only
have to take your phone out your pockets
and your screen Auto turns on and you're
blasted by notifications when the device
is on your face there's no escaping it
and that's also slightly worrying the
FaceTime thing also kind of creeped me
out so when you first set this headset
up you do a full 3D scan of your face
and from that point onwards whenever you
FaceTime what the other person sees is
technically a reconstruction of your
face instead of your actual face and at
least with the state that it's in right
now it does feel uncanny valley kind of
weird but the key thing that I don't
think any future revision of this
headset could ever solve is the
potential for isolation I am so
incredibly excited that this next era of
tech is here but I've never wanted and
not wanted a product to exist at the
same time as much as I do with this one
for the simple fact that I do think this
is the start of the end for shared
experiences at the end of the Apple
event where they were leading up to
announcing the price they were like you
know if you bought a massive TV and a
proper sound system you'd spend like 12K
but with this all of those things
together are just three and a half
thousand but the key thing that was
missing from that is that a cinema room
is an experience for a family this is an
experience for one I mean yeah you could
buy four or five for the entire family
and then technically watch the same film
all at once but what I imagine is a more
likely scenario is that everyone's
actually just watching their own thing
and that core human connection that
we've built up ever since we first
discovered fire and we've gathered
around it will start to fade and that
brings me onto the why why is Apple
doing this because I mean let's face it
this does not feel well timed the AR and
VR headset Market shrunk by like 50 last
year no one wants the metaverse people
don't like the idea of wearing a thing
over their head the whole time and at 3
500 this is not going to sell in the
quantities that the iPhone did well I
think this is an optimistic gamble I
think this is Apple having seen the
potential of VR and AR having seen that
it could potentially allow people to do
way more than their current phones can
and they're trying to win the market
early
to be honest I think they've got a
pretty good chance Apple has kind of a
reputation at this point for moving into
product categories not necessarily being
the first to enter them but dominating
them the iPod became the best-selling
MP3 player the iPhone the best-selling
smartphone the iPad the best-selling
tablet and the Apple watch the
best-selling Smartwatch and see Apple
has been secretly preparing for this
headset for years now they introduced
lidar scanners into the iPhone 12 Pro
for depth perception in the cameras
which as well as benefiting the iPhone
has silently been training developers on
how to best take advantage of lidar so
that this headset doesn't feel like a
sudden new developmental challenge for
them how they've been focusing really
hard on series Voice to Text engine
knowing that one day it may well be the
primary way to type things how a couple
of years ago they announced spatial
audio for airpods which tracks the
movement of your head and adds the
dimension of direction to your sound not
that useful for an iPhone but for a
headset that's designed around head
movements I mean it's pretty clear
that's what it's really made for no
other company has had an opportunity
like this to slowly gradually build up
all the separate ingredients of what
makes a headset like this and that's
what's allowed best to launch is a far
more Complete product than anyone else
has in their first gen and I honestly
don't know what other company is going
to be able to compete with it I think
apple is fully aware this is not about
to replace the iPhone now but it is
going to sit at the Pinnacle of Apple's
lineup and it's also pretty clear that
the ceiling thought this can do is way
higher and so if 10 years down the line
let's say the iPhone keeps plateauing
and this takes Leaps and Bounds and gets
Slimmer and lighter and way more
powerful I don't think it's unreasonable
for the iPhone to start to drift away
into being a legacy product one thing is
for sure they absolutely need developers
to get on board for this thing to pay
off this isn't like a watch where you
can just build some health apps and some
sleep tracking and that covers 90 of use
cases this is a platform that could
carry us for the next 20 years into the
future with applications that are far
bigger and more complex than anything
we've seen before at the same time of
course it's also arguably the hardest
Market to break into right now because
Apple has to not just make the best
products but they also have to change
the way that Society uses technology so
the purpose this video is not to say you
should go out and buy one of these but
it's validation the AR and VR are very
likely going to be the next chapter in
technology and now that this is out
there the use cases for it are about to
get a lot better very quickly if you
enjoyed this video then a sub to the
channel would be visionary
catch you in the next one